<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Way of the Animals</name>
        <description>Way of the Animals for Monk class from Tanares RPG 5e.</description>
        <author url="">Dragori Games</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="monk-animals.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/tanares/refs/heads/main/subclasses/monk-animals.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Way of the Animals" type="Archetype" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_MONK_ANIMALS">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Monks of the Way of the Animals embody the pinnacle of martial arts and wisdom, seeking to perfect their combat skills through a deep understanding of nature and the movements of different creatures. By blending and alternating between various animal stances, these monks have achieved a fluidity of body and spirit that is unmatched, expanding their Ki and granting them a broad and insightful perspective into the world.</p>
            <p class="indent">Not only are these monks masters of combat, but they also possess a unique worldview that is shaped by their connection to the animals they emulate. They see the world and those around them through the lens of different creatures, each with its own distinctive characteristics and traits. They might describe someone as cunning as a snake, determined like a tiger, precise like a praying mantis, cunning like a monkey, or unshakable like a dragon. This unique perspective has made the masters of the Way of the Animals be seen as wise sages, sought after by many who seek enlightenment and a deeper understanding of the world.</p>
            <div element="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_STANCE" />
            <div element="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_FLUID_MOVEMENTS" />
            <div element="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_AWARENESS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_STANCE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_KI" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_FLUID_MOVEMENTS" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_AWARENESS" level="17" />   
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Animal Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_STANCE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, you choose two of the six available animal stances. Each of these stances was created based on the observation of the fighting style of the creatures that named them: Crane, Monkey, Praying Mantis, Tiger, Snake, and Dragon. At 9th level, you learn another animal stance and another at 15th level. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switching Stances</strong>During the initiative roll, you must declare which animal stance you will be in at the start of combat. However, you can switch animal stance throughout battle in three ways:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spending a Ki Point:</strong> During your turn, you may spend 1 Ki Point to switch your animal stance. It does not consume any action and can only be performed once per turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Using the Switch Trigger of the Stance you are:</strong> If the Switch Trigger occurs, you may perform the Special Reaction described on your current Animal Stace to change to any other animal stance you know. You cannot use the Special Reaction and remain in the same Stance.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Using the Switch Trigger of another stance</strong>: If the Switch Trigger of another animal stance you know happens, you may perform the Special Reaction described on that Animal Stace to change your Stance to that same animal.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>Choose 2 stances. 1 more at level 9 and another at 15. You can change your stance by spending a ki point, using the Switch Trigger of your stance or another stance as a Special Reaction</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Stances (3)" supports="animal-stance" number="2" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Stances (9)" supports="animal-stance" number="1" level="9" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Stances (15)" supports="animal-stance" number="1" level="15"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Crane Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE" >
        <supports>animal-stance</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While in this animal stance, you have a +1 bonus to your AC.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> A creature within 5 feet of you declares an attack against your ally.</p> 
            <p class="indent"><strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can take a reaction to reduce the creature’s attack roll by half your proficiency bonus, rounded up</p>
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE_MOVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>+1 to AC. <strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> A creature within 5 feet of you declares an attack against your ally. <strong>Special Reaction:</strong>You can take a reaction to reduce the creature’s attack roll by half your proficiency bonus, rounded up</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="6" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE_KI" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="11" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Crane Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE_KI">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level while in Crane Stance, you can use your reaction and spend 2 Ki Points when you are targeted by an attack (before roll). This allows you to redirect the attack to another creature of your choice within 5 feet of you, excluding the original attacker. There must be a valid target available for you to use this ability, you cannot redirect an attack towards an emptyspace, the ground, or a wall.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Spend 2 ki points as a reaction when targeted by an attack to redirect to a creature within 5 feet of you, excluding the attacker.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="The Crane Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_CRANE_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level when you enter the Crane Stance, until the end of your next turn, the next attack against you has disadvantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you enter this stance, the next attack against you until the end of your next turn has disadvantage</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="The Monkey Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY" >
        <supports>animal-stance</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While in this animal stance, you do not spend Ki Points to perform Step of the Wind.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> If you are hit by an attack made by a creature in your line of sight.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can spend your Reaction to halve the damage done by this attack (rounded down).</p>
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY_MOVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>You do not spend Ki Points to perform Step of the Wind. <strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> If you are hit by an attack made by a creature in your line of sight. <strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can spend your Reaction to halve the damage done by this attack (rounded down).</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="6" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY_KI" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="11" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Monkey Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY_KI">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level while in Monkey Stance, you can spend 1 Ki Point when you perform a Step of the Wind. If you do, you can pass spaces occupied by enemies and do not receive attacks of opportunity while moving. After the move, you can take a Hide action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Spend 1 Ki Point during Step of the Wind to pass through enemy spaces without provoking attacks of opportunity and you may take the hide action after moving.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="The Monkey Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MONKEY_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level when you enter the Monkey Stance, you gain advantage on the next attack you make until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you enter this stance, you gain advantage on your next attack until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="The Praying Mantis Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS" >
        <supports>animal-stance</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While in this animal stance, you can use your bonus action to gain advantage on the next melee attack you make.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> If a creature within reach declares a melee attack against you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to make a melee attack, unarmed or using a monk weapon, against the creature that declared the attack before it makes the attack.</p>
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS_MOVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>You can use your bonus action to gain advantage on the next melee attack you make. <strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> If a creature within reach declares a melee attack against you. <strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to make a melee attack, unarmed or using a monk weapon, against the creature that declared the attack before it makes the attack.</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="6" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS_KI" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="11" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Praying Mantis Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS_KI">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level while in Praying Mantis Stance, if a humanoid creature fails its save against your Stunning Strike, you can spend 1 extra Ki Point to make the condition last for 1 minute instead of one turn. The creature can make a new saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect of success.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a creature fails it save against Stunning Strike, you can spend 1 Ki Point to make it last 1 minute. The creature can make new saves at the end of its turns.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="The Praying Mantis Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_MANTIS_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level when you enter the Praying Mantis Stance, the next creature you hit with an attack until the start of your next turn becomes prone.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you enter this stance, the next creature you hit with an attack until the start of your next turn becomes prone.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="The Tiger Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER" >
        <supports>animal-stance</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While in this animal stance, you deal one extra Martial Arts die of damage with the first melee attack you hit during your turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> An ally makes an attack against a creature within 5 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to make an unarmed strike or a monk weapon attack against that creature.</p>
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER_MOVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>You deal one extra Martial Arts die of damage with the first melee attack you hit during your turn. <strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> An ally makes an attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. <strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to make an unarmed strike or a monk weapon attack against that creature.</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="6" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER_KI" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="11" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Tiger Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER_KI">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level while in Tiger Stance, when you perform a Flurry of Blows, you can spend 1 extra Ki Point to perform one extra melee attack. If the attack succeeds, the target must make a Strength saving throw. On a fail, the creature is knocked prone and takes an extra 1d10 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You may spend a Ki Point during Fury of blows to permorm 1 extra melee attack. If it hits, the target makes a Strength Saving Throw and is knocked prone and takes 1d10 extra damage on fail.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="The Tiger Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_TIGER_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level when you enter the Tiger Stance, until the end of your next turn, the next attack you hit deals +1d10 damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you enter this stance, until the end of your next turn, the next attack you hit deals +1d10 damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="The Snake Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE" >
        <supports>animal-stance</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While in this animal stance, your Ki save DC is increased by 2</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switch Trigger:</strong>  A creature hostile to you moves to a space within 10 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to move to that creature immediately; it must make a Dexterity saving throw against your Ki save DC or have disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE_MOVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>Your Ki save DC is increased by 2. <strong>Switch Trigger:</strong>  A creature hostile to you moves to a space within 10 feet of you. <strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to move to that creature immediately; it must make a Dexterity saving throw against your Ki save DC or have disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="6" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE_KI" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="11" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Snake Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE_KI">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level while in Snake Stance, if you hit an unarmed strike with advantage against a creature, you can spend 1 Ki Point to impose a Constitution saving throw on the target. On a fail, the creature is afflicted by the poisoned condition for 1 minute, during which it takes 1d6 necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns to end the effect.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you hit an unarmed strike with advantage against a creature, you can spend 1 Ki Point to impose a Constitution saving throw on the target. On a fail, the creature is afflicted by the poisoned condition for 1 minute, during which it takes 1d6 necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="The Snake Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_SNAKE_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level when you enter the Snake Stance, until the end of your next turn, you gain advantage on the next attack you make. If you already have advantage on this attack, it becomes a critical hit if you hit</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you enter this stance, until the end of your next turn, you gain advantage on the next attack you make. If you already have advantage on this attack, it becomes a critical hit if you hit</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="The Dragon Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON" >
        <supports>animal-stance</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While you’re in this animal stance, any time you take damage of any kind, it’s reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus, but it can’t be reduced below 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> An ally within 5 feet of you becomes the target of an attack (before roll).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to become the target of this attack instead of your ally. If it hits you, any damage taken from this attack is halved (after applying all other forms of damage reduction).</p>
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON_KI" />
            <div element="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON_MOVEMENT" />            
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <p>Any time you take damage of any kind, it’s reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus, but it can’t be reduced below 1. <strong>Switch Trigger:</strong> An ally within 5 feet of you becomes the target of an attack (before roll).<strong>Special Reaction:</strong> You can use your Reaction to become the target of this attack instead of your ally. If it hits you, any damage taken from this attack is halved (after applying all other forms of damage reduction).</p>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="6" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON_KI" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" level="11" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Dragon Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON_KI">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level while in Dragon Stance, whenever you make a saving throw, you can spend 1 Ki Point to make it with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you make a saving throw, you can spend 1 Ki Point to make it with advantage</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="The Dragon Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMAL_ANIMAL_STANCE_DRAGON_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level when you enter the Dragon Stance, until the end of your next turn, all damage reductions incurred by the Dragon stance are doubled.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you enter this stance, until the end of your next turn, all damage reductions incurred by the Dragon stance are doubled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>


    <element name="Animal Ki" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_KI">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Ki Points to perform an ability that varies depending on the animal stance you are on.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Ki Points to perform an ability that varies depending on the animal stance you are on.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fluid Movements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_FLUID_MOVEMENTS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 11th level, your mastery of using fighting stances increases, and you gain an extra benefit whenever you enter a new animal stance.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain an extra benefit when you enter a new animal stance</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Animal Awareness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tanares RPG 5e" id="ID_TRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONK_ANIMALS_ANIMAL_AWARENESS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, you significantly develop your senses, similar to the animals whose movements define your martial art. You gain proficiency in Perception and Insight skills; if you are already proficient, double your proficiency bonus in that skill. In addition, you can never be surprised.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                <p>You can never be surprised</p>
            </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
             <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERCEPTION" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INSIGHT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>